/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d85c0c817f0398f9ff46"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-crack-the-UPSC-CSE-in-the-first-attempt-while-being-under-any-circumstances?-",
    "answer" : "Anand Mohan I will share my story and the strategy that I followed to clear the coveted Civil Services Exam in the first attempt. First of all, let me tell you a bit about myself. Civil services was never childhood dream. I did not start preparing from my school days and if anyone tells you that you need to start preparing from 8th standard, it is a myth and do not take them at face value. I did my B.Tech from College of Engineering, Trivandrum in Kerala. After graduating in 2015 I was working with ITC Limited, as a mechanical engineer. It was during my stint at ITC that I decided to prepare. So, I put in my papers in the June of 2016 and started preparing from July 2016. Term of preparation:- I started my preps from July 2016 and wrote Prelims in June 2017. So that is a total of 11 months of focused pre Continue Reading I will share my story and the strategy that I followed to clear the coveted Civil Services Exam in the first attempt. First of all, let me tell you a bit about myself. Civil services was never childhood dream. I did not start preparing from my school days and if anyone tells you that you need to start preparing from 8th standard, it is a myth and do not take them at face value. I did my B.Tech from College of Engineering, Trivandrum in Kerala. After graduating in 2015 I was working with ITC Limited, as a mechanical engineer. It was during my stint at ITC that I decided to prepare. So, I put in my papers in the June of 2016 and started preparing from July 2016. Term of preparation:- I started my preps from July 2016 and wrote Prelims in June 2017. So that is a total of 11 months of focused pre Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:38:52.078Z"),
    "question" : "How do I crack the UPSC CSE in the first attempt while being under any circumstances? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d86a0c817f0398f9ff4e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-jobs-after-UPSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Civil Service Exam :: Posts are : - ## Indian Administrative Service## Indian Foreign Service## Indian Revenue Service ( Customs & Central Excise)## Indian P & T Accounts & Finance Service## Indian Audit & Accounts Service## Indian Defence Accounts Service## Indian Revenue Service ( IT )## Indian Ordnance Factories Service## Indian Postal Service## Indian Civil Accounts Service## Indian Railway Accounts Service## Indian Railway Personnel Service## Indian Railway Traffic Service ## Post of Assistant Security Commissioner in Railway Protection Force## Indian Defence Estates Service.## Indian Information Service .## Indian Trade Service.## Indian Corporate Law Service.## Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service(Section Officer’s Grade).## Delhi, Andaman & Nicobar Islands, Laks Continue Reading Civil Service Exam :: Posts are : - ## Indian Administrative Service## Indian Foreign Service## Indian Revenue Service ( Customs & Central Excise)## Indian P & T Accounts & Finance Service## Indian Audit & Accounts Service## Indian Defence Accounts Service## Indian Revenue Service ( IT )## Indian Ordnance Factories Service## Indian Postal Service## Indian Civil Accounts Service## Indian Railway Accounts Service## Indian Railway Personnel Service## Indian Railway Traffic Service ## Post of Assistant Security Commissioner in Railway Protection Force## Indian Defence Estates Service.## Indian Information Service .## Indian Trade Service.## Indian Corporate Law Service.## Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service(Section Officer’s Grade).## Delhi, Andaman & Nicobar Islands, Laks Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:39:06.270Z"),
    "question" : "What are the jobs after UPSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d87d0c817f0398f9ff88"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-UPSC-2019?-",
    "answer" : "Naveen Kumar Chandra It’s almost an year to the 2019 CSE if I am not wrong. Which means, you have just the right amount of time for a perfect preparation. I would like to answer this question keeping in mind, an assumption, that you are a beginner. Now, first things first, you need to be aware of the examination, it’s process and most importantly, the syllabus and the pattern. I always tell aspirants that do your own research and become aware of the thing you are getting into, it might take a few days but it will make your mind clear that if you really wanna do it or it’s some superficial reason pushing you into this. CSE, is a 3 stage process, the prelims, the written exam and the personality test(called as mains combined). While the prelims is objective, written part of mains is subjective but the syllabus is a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:39:25.977Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for UPSC 2019? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d8980c817f0398f9ff93"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC-while-working?-",
    "answer" : "As a working professional one needs to keep in mind few things like:- how one will manage time for daily reading and note making- both for current affairs and the static portion.how one will manage holidays to optimize ones preparation.lastly, how one will ensure that they get quality guidance and one to one mentoring for accessing their preparation strategy, direction and quality.so you have to answer these 3 questions when you think of preparing while working. in this regards you should ideally take out 2–3 hrs daily either before office or after for reading. this is critical, as nothing can be achieved in UPSC preparation without consistency. also you have to be smart enough to study currrent affairs and newspaper either while commuting or during office break hours. After you are sticking Continue Reading As a working professional one needs to keep in mind few things like:- how one will manage time for daily reading and note making- both for current affairs and the static portion.how one will manage holidays to optimize ones preparation.lastly, how one will ensure that they get quality guidance and one to one mentoring for accessing their preparation strategy, direction and quality.so you have to answer these 3 questions when you think of preparing while working. in this regards you should ideally take out 2–3 hrs daily either before office or after for reading. this is critical, as nothing can be achieved in UPSC preparation without consistency. also you have to be smart enough to study currrent affairs and newspaper either while commuting or during office break hours. After you are sticking Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:39:52.628Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the UPSC while working? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d8ae0c817f0398f9ffa2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-was-your-timetable-while-preparing-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Krishna Dev Pathak Krishna",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:40:14.191Z"),
    "question" : "What was your timetable while preparing for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d8c50c817f0398f9ffc8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "The Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) is the central recruiting agency in India. It is an independent constitutional body in the sense that it is directly created by the constitution of India. The constitution contains elaborate provisions regarding the composition, appointment, and removal of members, powers and functions and independence of the UPSC. The constitution visualizes the UPSC to be the ‘watchdog of merit system’ in India. It is concerned with the recruitment to the All-India Services and Central Services-Group A and Group B and advises the government, when consulted, on promotion and disciplinary matters. The UPSC consists of a chairman and other members appointed by the president of India. The constitution does not specify the strength of commission but has left the matter  Continue Reading The Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) is the central recruiting agency in India. It is an independent constitutional body in the sense that it is directly created by the constitution of India. The constitution contains elaborate provisions regarding the composition, appointment, and removal of members, powers and functions and independence of the UPSC. The constitution visualizes the UPSC to be the ‘watchdog of merit system’ in India. It is concerned with the recruitment to the All-India Services and Central Services-Group A and Group B and advises the government, when consulted, on promotion and disciplinary matters. The UPSC consists of a chairman and other members appointed by the president of India. The constitution does not specify the strength of commission but has left the matter  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:40:37.040Z"),
    "question" : "What is UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d8f00c817f0398fa0005"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-manage-your-UPSC-preparation-with-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "Sumit Kumar Rai How did you manage your UPSC preparation with a job? 1.\tFirst of all, you need to have a mindset about your current job. It should be treated as a temporary phenomenon in your life. Assume that it is just a job, it is not something where you want to spend your entire life. Your passion and that burning desire for civil services should be your guiding criteria at your work place. So, treat your job as it is: It is secondary to your preparation. By this I don’t mean that you become too negligent at work. That should not be the case and an aspiring civil servant should never do that. You should have that adequate level of efficiency and professionalism and you should be able to complete all your deliverables within time. Don’t run after appraisals. Even if you get a bad one, it is not the end  Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:41:20.676Z"),
    "question" : "How did you manage your UPSC preparation with a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9020c817f0398fa000d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-It-possible-to-prepare-for-UPSC-while-working-in-an-IT-company?-",
    "answer" : "Pramod Singh Dear friend, You can prepare for UPSC and also can work simultaneously. It's totally depends on time management and your determination. Working as well as preparation can go side by side. In fact along with job there is more sense of urgency and disciplined approach. Lot of my students who were in IT sector are in service today and everyone of them went through similar dilemma. I have also been through the same scenario. I was working in working in Cognizant(2006–09) and I have devoted just one year to the preparation of civil services exam while working as it was means to meet my ends. I used to manage the time, by devoting 2-3 hours of my schedule to the preparation of civil services exam. I used to improve my basics in subject along with working on writing skills.Few days effort will not f Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:41:38.710Z"),
    "question" : "Is It possible to prepare for UPSC while working in an IT company? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9150c817f0398fa001d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-some-dark-sides-of-UPSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are some dark sides of UPSC exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:41:57.386Z"),
    "question" : "What are some dark sides of UPSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9270c817f0398fa002b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-quit-job-and-started-preparing-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Vishnu H Prasad, Indian Audit and Accounts ServiceAnswered 4 years ago · Author has 238 answers and 3.7M answer viewsShould I quit job and started preparing for UPSC? Vishnu H Prasad This took me back to the day when I was contemplating the same thing. Whether I should leave the safety and comfort of my well paying Engineering Job for something that I am not sure about. I think you should consider your background before you make a decision. If you have people depending on your income, then it wouldn't be wise to leave the job and keep them hanging. In my case that was not a pressing concern. If you have a girl friend, then you should consult her before you make such a decision. I did, and I should say that was the most prudent decision I took at the time. She is my wife today. This is a decision that will impact both of you. If you are not sure about yourself, take leave from work for some days and see if you still have it in you to study again. Sometimes the drudgery of  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:42:15.971Z"),
    "question" : "Should I quit job and started preparing for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d93a0c817f0398fa0050"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-crack-UPSC-with-my-current-9-to-5-job?-",
    "answer" : "Karan, IAS AspirantAnswered 4 years ago · Author has 85 answers and 333K answer viewsHow can I crack UPSC with my current 9-to-5 job? Karan Firstly, you have to decide where your priorities lie. If your No.1 priority is Civil Services then you should totally (yes I mean totally) dedicate yourself towards it. Even if you are working and can’t leave the job because of any reason it’s perfectly alright. But do remember this at the back of your mind that you have to put in your 200% because there are people who have the luxury of more time than you have. So basically you have to put double the effort in less than half the time if you desire to get a rank in your first attempt. Many people have cleared this exam while working, so there should be no reason why you can’t. Give yourself 2 years. Take it nice and easy bust be consistent with stuff. Studying only 3 hours on weekdays and about 12 hours on weekends would suffice but don't  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:42:34.610Z"),
    "question" : "How can I crack UPSC with my current 9-to-5 job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9740c817f0398fa0095"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-crack-UPSC-exam-with-a-private-job?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can I crack UPSC exam with a private job?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:43:32.658Z"),
    "question" : "Can I crack UPSC exam with a private job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d99d0c817f0398fa00af"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-start-preparing-for-UPSC-CSE-with-a-full-time-job?-",
    "answer" : "Lokesh Asopa Yes, anyone can crack UPSC CSE while doing a full-time job. I would like to share one example of Kajal Jwala, who got AIR 28(2018) in her fifth attempt. She was able to crack this exam without leaving her 9 hours long job and also without taking up any coaching. She was working for a multi-national company for the last 9 years and had a package of 23 lakh rupees annually. There is an enormous number of such students who set such benchmark of clearing UPSC CSE while remaining in Job. Although it takes a little longer time for them without proper guidance, but their sincerity, hard work, and dedication pave the way toward their goal. You just keep feeding your dream with a disciplined and consistent approach. If you prioritize your tasks well, optimize your efficiency and focus on productivity Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:44:13.418Z"),
    "question" : "How can I start preparing for UPSC CSE with a full time job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9ae0c817f0398fa00d4"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-jobs-for-a-UPSC-selected-candidate?-",
    "answer" : "Jobs for UPSC successful candidates:— If you are asking different posts under Civil Service Exam by Union Public Service Commission, the list is here :- All India Services (Group A) Indian Administrative Service (IAS)Indian Police Service (IPS)Central Services (Group A) Indian Audit and Accounts Service(IA&AS)Indian Civil Accounts Service (ICAS)Indian Corporate Law Service (ICLS)Indian Defence Accounts Service(IDAS)Indian Defence Estates Service(IDES)Indian Foreign Service (IFS)Indian Information Service (IIS)Indian Ordnance Factories Service(IOFS)Indian Post & Telecommunication Accounts and Finance Service(IP&TAFS)Indian Postal Service (IPoS)Indian Railway Accounts Service(IRAS)Indian Railway Personnel Service(IRPS)Indian Railway Traffic Service(IRTS)Indian Revenue Service (IRS-IT)Indian ReveContinue Reading Jobs for UPSC successful candidates:— If you are asking different posts under Civil Service Exam by Union Public Service Commission, the list is here :- All India Services (Group A) Indian Administrative Service (IAS)Indian Police Service (IPS)Central Services (Group A) Indian Audit and Accounts Service(IA&AS)Indian Civil Accounts Service (ICAS)Indian Corporate Law Service (ICLS)Indian Defence Accounts Service(IDAS)Indian Defence Estates Service(IDES)Indian Foreign Service (IFS)Indian Information Service (IIS)Indian Ordnance Factories Service(IOFS)Indian Post & Telecommunication Accounts and Finance Service(IP&TAFS)Indian Postal Service (IPoS)Indian Railway Accounts Service(IRAS)Indian Railway Personnel Service(IRPS)Indian Railway Traffic Service(IRTS)Indian Revenue Service (IRS-IT)Indian ReveContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:44:30.482Z"),
    "question" : "What are the jobs for a UPSC selected candidate? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9d30c817f0398fa00ea"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-both-for-SSC-CGL-and-UPSC-civil-service?-",
    "answer" : "Praveen Singh Can you prepare for both SSC CGL and CSE. It's like putting your foots in two different boats.  In today's world the government jobs are getting difficult every year. One cannot prepare for two different exams at same time like CGL and CSE. They may seem you same but they need different approach to prepare. In SSC CGL you have to prepare Quantitative aptitude, English, Reasoning and General Awareness. For tier 1 after clearing this stage you have to focus on QA and ENG for tier 2. Then tier 3 wher you have to write an essay or application. So the whole process of ssc exam is different from CSE. In CSE you have to prepare mostly general knowledge subject like history, polity, geography, environmental sciences etc. and If we talk about cset where English,Reasoning and aptitude questions asked one  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:45:07.966Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare both for SSC CGL and UPSC civil service? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035d9e80c817f0398fa0114"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-is-life-after-cracking-UPSC-versus-life-in-an-MNC-job?-",
    "answer" : "AnonymousAnswered 6 years agoHow is life after cracking UPSC versus life in an MNC job? Disclosure 1:This answer is copied from another quora answer. I have just copy pasted it. However I am also sailing in the same boat as writer of this answer is. One can give better inside of working enviornment of MNC. Hope then we  will get some better comparison. *Copy Paste start*Disclosure: I have to answer this anonymously as I am an IIT alumnus currently serving as a District Magistrate. My personal experience has not been very good and I plan to change my career path soon.  As the question specifically asks whether becoming a Civil Servant is a good option for an IITian or not, I have tried to answer that only. Hence, the reference to IITians.   Let me be very frank. I will not mince my words as I want to make sure that my IIT brethren are very clear about this career path. I feel  Continue Reading Disclosure 1:This answer is copied from another quora answer. I have just copy pasted it. However I am also sailing in the same boat as writer of this answer is. One can give better inside of working enviornment of MNC. Hope then we  will get some better comparison. *Copy Paste start*Disclosure: I have to answer this anonymously as I am an IIT alumnus currently serving as a District Magistrate. My personal experience has not been very good and I plan to change my career path soon.  As the question specifically asks whether becoming a Civil Servant is a good option for an IITian or not, I have tried to answer that only. Hence, the reference to IITians.   Let me be very frank. I will not mince my words as I want to make sure that my IIT brethren are very clear about this career path. I feel  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:45:28.486Z"),
    "question" : "How is life after cracking UPSC versus life in an MNC job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035da270c817f0398fa0152"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-SSC-CGL-post-is-best-suited-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Assistant Section Officer in Central Secretariat Service(CSS). Best SSC CGL post when it comes to UPSC preparation. Read further to be on same page as me . Every year SSC comes with 400–500 vacancies for this post. The competition is a bit tough but still its easier to get this post compared to others like MEA, ITI, Examiner etc (Cutoff a bit lower due to CPT ). Now let’s discuss why this is the best post for a UPSC aspirant? The posting is always in New Delhi. Half the work is done when there is a good start !!New Delhi is undoubtedly the mecca of UPSC CSE preparation. One can get himself/herself enrolled in best coaching available.( From ALS to Vajiram, everybody is here).Availability to best study material (From standard books to printed material of coaching notes, everything at stone’s tContinue Reading Assistant Section Officer in Central Secretariat Service(CSS). Best SSC CGL post when it comes to UPSC preparation. Read further to be on same page as me . Every year SSC comes with 400–500 vacancies for this post. The competition is a bit tough but still its easier to get this post compared to others like MEA, ITI, Examiner etc (Cutoff a bit lower due to CPT ). Now let’s discuss why this is the best post for a UPSC aspirant? The posting is always in New Delhi. Half the work is done when there is a good start !!New Delhi is undoubtedly the mecca of UPSC CSE preparation. One can get himself/herself enrolled in best coaching available.( From ALS to Vajiram, everybody is here).Availability to best study material (From standard books to printed material of coaching notes, everything at stone’s tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:46:31.790Z"),
    "question" : "Which SSC CGL post is best suited for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035da3b0c817f0398fa015e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-necessary-to-write-a-UPSC-exam-to-become-an-IAS-officer?-",
    "answer" : "There are 2 ways of becoming IAS Officer without even attempting UPSC Civil Service examination. There are as follows : State Civil Service : All states in India have their State PCS exam. Whichever state you belong to, try to score single digit rank in PCS and you can easily secure Deputy Collector post. In a span of 15–20 years, depending upon the State and your performance (plus some luck), you would be promoted to IAS Cadre. Do you know that 33% of All India IAS posts are reserved for State PCS Officers.Sports Quota : As we all know there is a Sports Quota in Government Jobs. Do you know this man ? Joginder Sharma. Indian Cricketer who helped India win 2007 T20 Word Cup. He is now DSP in Haryana Police. Try to win international medal like in Asian Games, Commonwealth Games etc. [ Olympics  Continue Reading There are 2 ways of becoming IAS Officer without even attempting UPSC Civil Service examination. There are as follows : State Civil Service : All states in India have their State PCS exam. Whichever state you belong to, try to score single digit rank in PCS and you can easily secure Deputy Collector post. In a span of 15–20 years, depending upon the State and your performance (plus some luck), you would be promoted to IAS Cadre. Do you know that 33% of All India IAS posts are reserved for State PCS Officers.Sports Quota : As we all know there is a Sports Quota in Government Jobs. Do you know this man ? Joginder Sharma. Indian Cricketer who helped India win 2007 T20 Word Cup. He is now DSP in Haryana Police. Try to win international medal like in Asian Games, Commonwealth Games etc. [ Olympics  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:46:51.688Z"),
    "question" : "Is it necessary to write a UPSC exam to become an IAS officer? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035da4d0c817f0398fa0170"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-happens-after-clearing-the-UPSC-examination?-What-job-do-we-get-for-which-rank?-What-happens-during-training,-and-what-is-the-pay-scale?-",
    "answer" : "The results for the UPSC Civil Service Examination are generally declared within a week after the completion of the interviews - this has been the trend in the last two years. Once the results are declared, the following things happen - UPSC declares the cut off marks for Prelims and Mains examinations, along with the overall cut off. This is followed by the detailed marksheet (Prelims + Mains + Interview) for those who appeared for Mains Examination and passed in the Qualifying papers (Regional language and English).The answer keys for Prelims exam is then declared.Now the fate of those in the UPSC merit list shifts to the Department of Personnel and Training (DoPT) which, I have felt, is not as efficient as UPSC. Service allocation, which is done by DoPT based on rank and category of the Continue Reading The results for the UPSC Civil Service Examination are generally declared within a week after the completion of the interviews - this has been the trend in the last two years. Once the results are declared, the following things happen - UPSC declares the cut off marks for Prelims and Mains examinations, along with the overall cut off. This is followed by the detailed marksheet (Prelims + Mains + Interview) for those who appeared for Mains Examination and passed in the Qualifying papers (Regional language and English).The answer keys for Prelims exam is then declared.Now the fate of those in the UPSC merit list shifts to the Department of Personnel and Training (DoPT) which, I have felt, is not as efficient as UPSC. Service allocation, which is done by DoPT based on rank and category of the Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:47:09.617Z"),
    "question" : "What happens after clearing the UPSC examination? What job do we get for which rank? What happens during training, and what is the pay scale? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035da5e0c817f0398fa0197"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-a-good-decision-to-quit-a-job-and-prepare-for-the-UPSC-civil-services?-",
    "answer" : "Abhinav Kumar Singh Its not a big thing nowadays to quit job and prepare for studies/job opportunities. But there are following things you should check with yourself when you decide on that:- Prepare your Plan B before signing off. I mean what if you don't get the job and wish to return to \"an acceptable Plan B\" in that scenario. So define that Plan B and ensure that it is not probable but a certainty.How will you fund your existing liabilities plus the future expenses? Say you need a year to prepare for your studies. So how do you see funding your 12 months expenses plus any other monthly liabilities (Loan EMI, Funds to family, etc).Have a test run before taking the plunge. At least for a month or two try and create an environment of you without a job and having to study. That will give you some valuable inContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:47:26.616Z"),
    "question" : "Is it a good decision to quit a job and prepare for the UPSC civil services? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035da960c817f0398fa01d2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-highest-paid-position-in-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "You can read this one by one under there services. Indian Administrative Service Pay Scale Rs. 56100 to Rs.2,50,000 per month depending on rank List of posts:Under SecretaryDeputy SecretaryDirector Joint SecretaryAdditional SecretarySecretaryCabinet SecretaryAdditional District Magistrate Joint SecretaryDistrict Magistrate (DM)Deputy Commissioner Special SecretaryHead of Departments SecretaryPrincipal Secretary, Financial CommissionerChief Secretary Constitutional Authority Indian Police Service Salary Rs. 39000 to Rs. 2,12,650 per month depending on rank List of postsAssistant Superintendent of PoliceSuperintendent of PoliceAssistant Director in Central Police Organizations Commandant in Armed Police Senior Superintendent of police Deputy Inspector General of Police Deputy D Continue Reading You can read this one by one under there services. Indian Administrative Service Pay Scale Rs. 56100 to Rs.2,50,000 per month depending on rank List of posts:Under SecretaryDeputy SecretaryDirector Joint SecretaryAdditional SecretarySecretaryCabinet SecretaryAdditional District Magistrate Joint SecretaryDistrict Magistrate (DM)Deputy Commissioner Special SecretaryHead of Departments SecretaryPrincipal Secretary, Financial CommissionerChief Secretary Constitutional Authority Indian Police Service Salary Rs. 39000 to Rs. 2,12,650 per month depending on rank List of postsAssistant Superintendent of PoliceSuperintendent of PoliceAssistant Director in Central Police Organizations Commandant in Armed Police Senior Superintendent of police Deputy Inspector General of Police Deputy D Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:48:22.031Z"),
    "question" : "What is the highest paid position in UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dadd0c817f0398fa0215"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-enter-into-UPSC-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How can I enter into UPSC jobs?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:49:33.044Z"),
    "question" : "How can I enter into UPSC jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035daf10c817f0398fa0221"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-source-for-world-geography-in-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "World geography for UPSC can be covered from following sources: Old NCERT Geography books from Class 6 to 8: The presentation of these books are very unique. These books cover the physical and human geography of entire world continent-wise in a very lucid and yet elaborative manner. Click on the link to download old NCERT books: Old NCERT Books PDF (History, Geography, etc.) - Notes CluesCertificate Physical and Human Geography by G C Leong: It is the best book for World Geography in market. For world geography, special focus needs to be given on Part-II of the book which illustrates the physical and human geography of entire world based on climate-regions.Atlas (either Orient Blackswan or Oxford): Atlas is must for world geography. Atlas must go hand-in-hand with above mentioned books.Besi Continue Reading World geography for UPSC can be covered from following sources: Old NCERT Geography books from Class 6 to 8: The presentation of these books are very unique. These books cover the physical and human geography of entire world continent-wise in a very lucid and yet elaborative manner. Click on the link to download old NCERT books: Old NCERT Books PDF (History, Geography, etc.) - Notes CluesCertificate Physical and Human Geography by G C Leong: It is the best book for World Geography in market. For world geography, special focus needs to be given on Part-II of the book which illustrates the physical and human geography of entire world based on climate-regions.Atlas (either Orient Blackswan or Oxford): Atlas is must for world geography. Atlas must go hand-in-hand with above mentioned books.Besi Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:49:53.172Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best source for world geography in UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db020c817f0398fa022d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-leave-my-job-and-start-for-UPSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Akarsh Jaisingh Ofcourse yes,if you are passionate enough for civil services you should quit your job if everything is fine in your family like economic condition and no one is dependent on you for money ,you should go for it else you have to continue the job while preparing for the exams..but I guess 10–12 months is enough to prepare for UPSC if you have everything handy like notes, books or online materials.. nowadays everything is available online so you don't need to attend for offline classes..all you need is a focused mind and determination towards your goal.. ofcourse you might have got inspired by reading anyone's story who has cracked the exam..so you should also have an aim that you can do it and be sure enough to sacrifice your fun activities and limit to a fixed time shedule..so it totally dep Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:50:10.673Z"),
    "question" : "Should I leave my job and start for UPSC preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db180c817f0398fa0256"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-the-SSC-CGL-and-the-UPSC-IRS-in-terms-of-careers-and-job-roles?-",
    "answer" : "Sangam Garg Let’s first talk about SSC CGL Through CGL you will join either at the rank of Tax Assistant or Inspector Let’s say you join at rank of Tax Assistant which is 2400 grade pay. After 4–5 years you will get promoted to Senior Tax Assistant which is 4200 grade pay. Now after another 3–4 years you will get promoted to Income Tax Inspector which is 4600 grade pay. Now Inspector gets promoted to Income Tax Officer (4800 grade pay) after 5–8 years . Officer gets promoted to Assistant Commissioner (5400 grade pay) after 10–12 years. Now Assistant Commissioner is rank which you get directly from UPSC IRS. If you join at rank of Inspector then you will become IRS after 15–20 years in that time period a direct IRS candidate will reach rank of Additional Commissioner or Commissioner. I hope you understood the Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:50:32.491Z"),
    "question" : "What is the difference between the SSC CGL and the UPSC IRS in terms of careers and job roles? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db2d0c817f0398fa0263"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-a-time-table-for-the-UPSC-2016-while-being-in-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "Vinay Shukla",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:50:53.085Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare a time table for the UPSC 2016 while being in a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db3f0c817f0398fa0271"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-appear-UPSC-without-quitting-my-present-job?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Can I appear UPSC without quitting my present job?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:51:11.731Z"),
    "question" : "Can I appear UPSC without quitting my present job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db520c817f0398fa0297"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-people-working-in-a-9-5-job-study-for-UPSC-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do people working in a 9-5 job study for UPSC exams?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:51:30.032Z"),
    "question" : "How do people working in a 9-5 job study for UPSC exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db760c817f0398fa02b1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-the-UPSC-check-the-private-job-experience-after-selection?-",
    "answer" : "Kulbhushan Bhade Kishore Raju Vipul Singh",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:52:06.223Z"),
    "question" : "Will the UPSC check the private job experience after selection? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035db8a0c817f0398fa02db"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-IAS-coaching-centers-in-Mumbai?-",
    "answer" : "As per my knowledge, there are many institutes in Mumbai stating that they are teaching or guiding us for Union Public Service Commission Civil Services Examination very well but don’t. I wasted my 2 years precious time then I visited The Prayas India Thane center and met with Mr. Mohammad Shahid Ansari, he guided me properly I wrote second time mains only because of Shahid Sir and The Prayas India Mentor team. I hope your self-study can help you to crack this exam but will take time and even if you want to crack this exam by your self-study at least once you should meet with any one of the Mentor of The Prayas India, Mentors name are Amresh Aryan, Shahid Sir, Hrishikesh Sir, Akhil Sir, Samar Sir etc. And if you want to join or seeking help for your UPSC CSE study then go only to The Prayas  Continue Reading As per my knowledge, there are many institutes in Mumbai stating that they are teaching or guiding us for Union Public Service Commission Civil Services Examination very well but don’t. I wasted my 2 years precious time then I visited The Prayas India Thane center and met with Mr. Mohammad Shahid Ansari, he guided me properly I wrote second time mains only because of Shahid Sir and The Prayas India Mentor team. I hope your self-study can help you to crack this exam but will take time and even if you want to crack this exam by your self-study at least once you should meet with any one of the Mentor of The Prayas India, Mentors name are Amresh Aryan, Shahid Sir, Hrishikesh Sir, Akhil Sir, Samar Sir etc. And if you want to join or seeking help for your UPSC CSE study then go only to The Prayas  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:52:26.980Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best IAS coaching centers in Mumbai? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dbb30c817f0398fa02f1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-Surabhi-Gautam-prepare-for-UPSC-while-doing-her-job?-",
    "answer" : "Kumar Ummareddy, CEO Mata Enterprises  (1997-present)Answered 11 months ago · Author has 2.6K answers and 25.9M answer viewsWhat is the daily routine of Surabhi Gautam while preparing for UPSC, is she an extreme night owl? Kumar Ummareddy Meet this beautiful Surabhi Gautam IAS. AIR 50 -2016.  Shares Tips On How To Crack The Exam Cracking the UPSC examination is a feat many candidates attempt year-on-year, but only a few manage to clear. From the way they prepared to the books they referred and the tips they wish to share with aspirants, this series will attempt to answer them all. Surabhi Gautam, All India Rank 50 (UPSC 2016), is currently serving as the Assistant Collector at Vadodara, Gujarat. Choose wisely Surabhi begins, “Be extremely precise and specific about your optional subject. Remember that the difference between aspirant ‘A’ and aspirant ‘B’ actually lies in which optional subject they choose.” You could either chose on the basis of your graduation or post-graduation subjects or go for any popular optional subject like  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:53:07.504Z"),
    "question" : "How did Surabhi Gautam prepare for UPSC while doing her job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dbc80c817f0398fa031b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-worth-getting-in-to-UPSC-ESE-job-at-age-27?-",
    "answer" : "Current superannuation limit is 60 years for Grade A officers(which may increase to 62 years in near future). Lets assume the superannuation limit sticks to 60 years and you get into ESE at 27 years of age, you have 33 years of services available with you. It is a healthy span of period to serve. Moreover once you get into the service,you will be so indulged in the work that you won't have the thoughts about how many years you served. Abhishek Benjamin",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:53:28.670Z"),
    "question" : "Is it worth getting in to UPSC ESE job at age 27? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dbee0c817f0398fa0331"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-group-C-jobs-in-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Should I prepare for the UPSC instead of SSC since the latter takes a lot of time to give you a job? Almost 2 years till posting, so should I rather spend 1 year extra for UPSC preparation?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:54:06.610Z"),
    "question" : "What are group C jobs in the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dc040c817f0398fa035b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-for-me-to-crack-UPSC-along-with-a-9-to-5-job?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is it possible for me to crack UPSC along with a 9-to-5 job?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:54:28.160Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible for me to crack UPSC along with a 9-to-5 job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dc4b0c817f0398fa039b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-anyone-who-cracks-UPSC-while-doing-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "My Answer is Yes. The main thing is Time management. If, you are good in Time management. It would be possible for You. But,My View is on Some things like Make Better relationship with your seniors or manager.Job Environment ( Internet usage, easily access any good coaching centres, Normal workload)Prefer Fixed time Job.ALL THE BEST FOR YOUR FUTURE.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:55:39.250Z"),
    "question" : "Is there anyone who cracks UPSC while doing a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dc800c817f0398fa03d7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-upsc-doing-bank-po-job-or-any-other-job?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, If you grit and passion you can definitely crack the upsc exam. One of my acquaintance has got job in Band PO. He has a lot of time for preparation for upsc. Right now he is preparing for RAS(rajasthan administrator services). So start studying , get good books and do it.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:56:32.017Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack upsc doing bank po job or any other job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dc9a0c817f0398fa03eb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-post-is-good-for-a-UPSC-aspirant-in-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "There is no job perfect for preparation for an exam like UPSC Civil Services BUT …. Perfection is only a myth, right !! So, There are some specific needs which should be fulfilled. Travel should be minimum or Zero.No frequent transfers should be there.Fixed timings in job so that a study timetable can be maintained.Salary should be sufficient to pay for preparation , coaching and regular life.Posting place should have some coaching and atmosphere of preparation.It would be better if some colleagues are also keen to prepare or are already preparing. A study group can be formed.Seniors should be supportive.Workload in job should be moderate. This is not always possible but helpful.Posting place should have all necessary facilities.Good availability of accommodation.All the above requirements a Continue Reading There is no job perfect for preparation for an exam like UPSC Civil Services BUT …. Perfection is only a myth, right !! So, There are some specific needs which should be fulfilled. Travel should be minimum or Zero.No frequent transfers should be there.Fixed timings in job so that a study timetable can be maintained.Salary should be sufficient to pay for preparation , coaching and regular life.Posting place should have some coaching and atmosphere of preparation.It would be better if some colleagues are also keen to prepare or are already preparing. A study group can be formed.Seniors should be supportive.Workload in job should be moderate. This is not always possible but helpful.Posting place should have all necessary facilities.Good availability of accommodation.All the above requirements a Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:56:58.603Z"),
    "question" : "Which post is good for a UPSC aspirant in the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dcaf0c817f0398fa0417"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-UPSC-while-working-a-Central-Goverment-job?-",
    "answer" : "Yes,why not? There is no problem to prepare with job. One thing you should do ,make a proper time schedule according to your convenience. Make a time table of (before & after) of time which left after the service.Use the time of your traveling during office . If you are new then first of all take the UPSC syllabus print out and understand it thoroughly.A after it go with basic books like & NCERT. There are many in recent years who cleared the exam with job. You can take help from there interview on you tube. 1 rank Anudeep 44 rank Abhilash Barnwal Feel free to contact. Thanks",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:57:19.861Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for UPSC while working a Central Goverment job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dce40c817f0398fa0436"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-clear-upsc-in-first-attempt-with-job-10-to-7?-",
    "answer" : "David Harry Reethu Shabi Sumant Sahay",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:58:12.881Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to clear upsc in first attempt with job 10 to 7? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd0d0c817f0398fa0466"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-do-a-job-simultaneously-with-UPSC-preparation-because-I-want-to-do-a-job-for-a-few-years-along-with-my-UPSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Shubham Satyam",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:58:53.741Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to do a job simultaneously with UPSC preparation because I want to do a job for a few years along with my UPSC preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd220c817f0398fa0476"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-RBI-Grade-B-the-most-coveted-government-job-in-India-after-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Anil Jhajharia Aah.. Yet another question that equates Grade B post to ultimatum in a person’s career. The only answer I would like to give to all these questions circulating in quora is a BIGGGGG NOO!!!!. Realise the following facts First of all you should realise that this is just a recruitment for “MANAGERIAL POST”. As a manager, you will be asked to guide a team of 4 or 5 Assistants in a Department headed by DGM or a GM.There are many other similar posts in Govt sector that offers much more package and power such as Sebi Grade A, ONGC GET, IES , DRDO/ISRO SCIENTISTS etc. Just that they are not in limelight and not marketed by the so called online package dealers.DONT FALL INTO THE TRAP OF DTY. GOVERNOR RUMOUR!!! The chance of a Grade B ending up as Deputy Governor is much much lesser than you pairing Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:59:14.515Z"),
    "question" : "Is RBI Grade B the most coveted government job in India after the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd330c817f0398fa049b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-difficult-getting-a-job-after-taking-a-year-break-for-UPSC-preparations?-",
    "answer" : "Mahendra Patil I think your concern is if you quit the job for kne year and then if required you will get the job again or not. Well, I was also gonna do that once when I was in my previous company. But after analysing myself I came to know that I was not even utilizing the free time I was getting before and after office work hours, then how can I guarantee myself that I will make best use of that very much time after quitting my job. I suggest to at least start the preparation during free time of you have not started. Get synchronized with subjects, current affairs. After that when you feel your job is consuming the extra time you could have given for studies, quitting the job may be taken into consideration. In my view, as I am in IT field, quitting and getting the job again should not be difficult if can Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T04:59:31.555Z"),
    "question" : "Is it difficult getting a job after taking a year break for UPSC preparations? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd5a0c817f0398fa04b2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-do-so-many-UPSC-aspirants-leave-their-comfortable-and-well-paying-corporate-jobs-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Awdhesh Singh There are many reasons for top paying corporate honchos to join civil services. Let me list a few of them. 1: Service Some youngsters join civil services for serving the nation by joining the government. Poltics is a difficult path and it takes seevral years to succeed in poltics. You can join civil services and you can directly serve the people directly as a civil servant. 2: Power and Perks Many people are attracted towards the power of the civil servants. They desire the red-light cars, police escorts, big bungalows, cars and fleet of servants at the houses of DM/SP and they want to enjoy those power and parks. 3: Ignorance Most people in India don’t know much about civil services. They know about the top services like IAS and IPS and don’t know that there are almost two dozen services for wh Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:00:10.741Z"),
    "question" : "Why do so many UPSC aspirants leave their comfortable and well-paying corporate jobs for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd6c0c817f0398fa04da"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/With-which-job-can-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:00:28.768Z"),
    "question" : "With which job can I prepare for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dd8f0c817f0398fa04f0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-someone-prepare-for-the-UPSC-being-in-a-job-via-the-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Awdhesh Singh, former Author: 31 Ways to Happiness| IITian| Ex-IRS  at Government of India (1991-2016)Updated 2 years ago · Upvoted by Subhadip Debnath, Multi Tasking Staff at Staff Selection Commission (2018-present) and Anil Jhajharia, IRS-IT designated  at Government of India (2018-present) · Author has 5.3K answers and 172.1M answer viewsCan someone prepare for the UPSC being in a job via the SSC? Awdhesh Singh",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:01:03.761Z"),
    "question" : "Can someone prepare for the UPSC being in a job via the SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ddb40c817f0398fa051e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-prepare-for-an-SSC-CGL-and-UPSC-from-August-2018-and-at-least-get-a-job-in-the-SSC-and-start-my-UPSC-preparation-from-there?-",
    "answer" : "Aliyaz Aliyaz Sk UPSC Bumper Job Opening for Graduates and Post Graduates, Apply Here.  Union Public Service Commission (UPSC) published an official notification, inviting applications for the appointment of candidates on the post of Air Safety Officer, Assistant Director and others on contract basis. Candidates with graduation and post graduation degree are eligible to apply for this job opening. Interested candidates must apply for this post before its last date. More detailed information related to this post like age limit, pay band, qualifications etc. are mentioned below: Who is Eligible to apply for this post? Graduation degree holders are eligible to apply for this post. How much can you earn from this post? Candidates will be paid according to their posts. Deadline to apply for this post? Interested applicants Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:01:40.509Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to prepare for an SSC CGL and UPSC from August 2018 and at least get a job in the SSC and start my UPSC preparation from there? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ddc40c817f0398fa052e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-do-youth-are-interested-in-UPSC-to-be-an-IAS-or-IPS-to-work-under-illiterate-politicians-whereas-high-paid-jobs-are-there-in-corporate?-",
    "answer" : "Jerin Koickalethu Once a senior most political leader asked a bureaucrat ,“Don't you feel bad listening and complying with our orders even though we people being much below in qualification as compared to you?” The answer to this was epic, he replied stating that sir we listen to the chair not the person, you are a people's representative and we are adhering to people's choice by listening to your orders. In a democracy, at the end the supreme power is with the people. All of them ranging from ministers to bureaucrats are public servants. Only difference is ministers and others in the top hierarchy are political executive (having certain tenure) while civil servants are permanent executive (serving till retirement). While on the other side, not all politicians are illiterate. People generally make pre concei Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:01:56.705Z"),
    "question" : "Why do youth are interested in UPSC to be an IAS or IPS to work under illiterate politicians whereas high paid jobs are there in corporate? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ddd50c817f0398fa053b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-manage-to-clear-the-UPSC-CSE-along-with-your-job?-",
    "answer" : "I have come across many students who are working and aspiring to clear the civil services exam. There is a good news and a bad news. The bad news is that it is difficult. You will be competing with students who are preparing full time, with students who are writing their 3rd, 4th or 5th attempt, with students who have already cleared the exam and are writing it again for their rank improvement. They all are putting way more efforts than you while you are fighting to get the leave approvals from your boss. The good news is, that despite all this, every year, there are aspirants who manage to clear the exam while being in a job. If they can do it, why can’t you? The key is strategic planning and giving enough time. For example. if you are a working candidate and decide to write the IAS 2019 which is merely 5 months away, it is going to be difficult. But, if we target 2020 at this time, it will be easier and doable. As far as the answer to your question is concerned, the first step should be for you to make a strategy! What to do? When to do that? What has to follow what? What is the number of hours you can bring out and how to make full use of them. Once this strategy is clear, all other things will automatically fall into place. To help you build the same, spare 10 minutes and watch this video. Currently, this is the most updated IAS 2020 strategy. If you have any query, call me on 7087000446 and I will guide you on a few things more.  Wishing you All the best!",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:02:13.270Z"),
    "question" : "How did you manage to clear the UPSC CSE along with your job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ddea0c817f0398fa0562"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Have-you-ever-left-an-IT-job-and-prepare-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Jagtar Malwa Vandita Hiremath",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:02:34.599Z"),
    "question" : "Have you ever left an IT job and prepare for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ddfa0c817f0398fa056c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-to-prepare-for-upsc-while-doing-shift-job?-",
    "answer" : "Amol Mungusmare",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:02:50.786Z"),
    "question" : "How to prepare for upsc while doing shift job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de1d0c817f0398fa05a0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-options-I-have-when-I-write-upsc-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Question URL: quora. com/unanswered/What-jobs-we-would-get-if-we-write-UPSC #Questionnn name:: What jobs we would get if we write UPSC? TOP 9 SITES TO FIND WORK AS A FRREELANCER: There are plenty of guides for striking out on your own, but as a frreelancer, getting higher-paying gigs isn’t just a matter of signing up on popular platforms. You’ll have to branch out, establish a great portfolio of past work and maybe even prove yourself through tests that showcase your skills. Here’s a list of the best sites to find work as a frreelancer. #1. BloggingPro The BloggingPro job board is mostly for bloggers. On this site, you can blog about almost anything. Here several employers are looking for people who can write on an array of subjects. #2. FreelanceWriter88 .info This is one of the best sites for w Continue Reading Question URL: quora. com/unanswered/What-jobs-we-would-get-if-we-write-UPSC #Questionnn name:: What jobs we would get if we write UPSC? TOP 9 SITES TO FIND WORK AS A FRREELANCER: There are plenty of guides for striking out on your own, but as a frreelancer, getting higher-paying gigs isn’t just a matter of signing up on popular platforms. You’ll have to branch out, establish a great portfolio of past work and maybe even prove yourself through tests that showcase your skills. Here’s a list of the best sites to find work as a frreelancer. #1. BloggingPro The BloggingPro job board is mostly for bloggers. On this site, you can blog about almost anything. Here several employers are looking for people who can write on an array of subjects. #2. FreelanceWriter88 .info This is one of the best sites for w Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:03:25.425Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job options I have when I write upsc exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de320c817f0398fa05ac"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-candidates-with-job-experience-given-preference-in-the-UPSC-interview?-",
    "answer" : "Zahir Shaikh  Before the Interview board everyone is considered equal. That is why people say it may be the only board where personality is tested. Your IQ and knowledge level required for the job has been already tested in the Preliminary and Mains examination. Many freshers get into the service. Hence job experience does not play a big role in the interview, though may be the skills you acquired shall helpful in the interview.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:03:46.006Z"),
    "question" : "Are candidates with job experience given preference in the UPSC interview? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de440c817f0398fa05b7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-a-bank-PO-job-more-stressful-and-time-consuming-than-UPSC-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, it is even more stressful than being the Prime Minister of a country. I mean, a bank PO has to look after almost everything in the branch, he has to run the branch actually, run it smoothly. Mind you, just a branch though. Imagine, you are posted far away from your home, where you have 3–5 clerks under you to manage(might vary) , 1–2 officers who are your counterparts and a branch head whom you report to, footfall of around 150–200 customers a day. Yes, your day is fucked up and hell lot hectic.Angry customers, customers with complaints, internal staff issues, staff politics, technology related constraints, I know you are under stress and your day is full of workload and all that shit. My sympathies are with you. Mind you, you are just handling a branch though. Now imagine the plight of Continue Reading Yes, it is even more stressful than being the Prime Minister of a country. I mean, a bank PO has to look after almost everything in the branch, he has to run the branch actually, run it smoothly. Mind you, just a branch though. Imagine, you are posted far away from your home, where you have 3–5 clerks under you to manage(might vary) , 1–2 officers who are your counterparts and a branch head whom you report to, footfall of around 150–200 customers a day. Yes, your day is fucked up and hell lot hectic.Angry customers, customers with complaints, internal staff issues, staff politics, technology related constraints, I know you are under stress and your day is full of workload and all that shit. My sympathies are with you. Mind you, you are just handling a branch though. Now imagine the plight of Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:04:04.706Z"),
    "question" : "Is a bank PO job more stressful and time consuming than UPSC jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de570c817f0398fa05e1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-clear-UPSC-while-doing-a-job-in-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "Yes, you can . But it will depend on your hard work. Nothing can be assured as UPSC civil services exam is unpredicatble. But i think you will get enough time to prepare for UPSC civil services with a backup job. In 2015, Bandana Pokhriyal(Rank 83), cleared UPSC civil services while working as Excise Inspector. You can see the attached link for your reference. MOTIVATION: Bandana Pokhriyal, Rank - 83, Cleared UPSC Civil Services Without Quitting Job While Working as Excise Inspector for Past 4.5 Years - INSIGHTS Ravi Pandey",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:04:23.776Z"),
    "question" : "Can I clear UPSC while doing a job in SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de7a0c817f0398fa05f2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-average-salary-after-getting-a-job-in-the-geological-survey-of-India-through-the-UPSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Jibanjyoti Routray",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:04:58.519Z"),
    "question" : "What is the average salary after getting a job in the geological survey of India through the UPSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035de9b0c817f0398fa0622"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-government-job-is-the-best-for-preparation-for-the-UPSC-with-a-study-leave?-",
    "answer" : "It appears you are taking government job too lightly which unfortunately is not the case. sometimes they are highly demanding. If you really want to prepare for UPSC seriously and still need to work, better take up a part time job until your exams are over.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:05:31.769Z"),
    "question" : "Which government job is the best for preparation for the UPSC with a study leave? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035ded40c817f0398fa0660"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-government-job-is-better-in-terms-of-money-and-power-apart-from-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Tina Sharma Dev Patil",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:06:28.195Z"),
    "question" : "Which government job is better in terms of money and power apart from UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dee70c817f0398fa066b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-I-motivate-myself-to-quit-my-15-LPA-job-and-go-for-the-UPSC-exams-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "My dear friend, I have been working in a MNC for past 1.5 years. I now have a package of 14lpa. Now, I resigned and started my preparation for 2016 exam. My advise to you is to take up the job. Why? A voice is asking you become IAS officer: This is not sufficient for taking up this job. You need to look at some more practicalities.  a) Exam Result: Some academically well qualified people did not achieve their targets in the exam. You may fail in prelims, if passed may fail in mains, if passed may not qualify for any services. Even if you make to the final list of recommended candidates, you may get any service not just IAS, IPS. Even, if you get IAS or IPS cadre, depending on your rank, you may get Assam, Meghalaya cadre. Are you ready for it? Believe me. This is the most important question. Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:06:47.197Z"),
    "question" : "How should I motivate myself to quit my 15-LPA job and go for the UPSC exams preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035defa0c817f0398fa067b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-makes-the-UPSC-so-special?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:07:06.921Z"),
    "question" : "What makes the UPSC so special? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035df0f0c817f0398fa06a5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-be-preparing-for-UPSC-by-quitting-a-well-paying-job?-",
    "answer" : "Sandeep Answer is with in yourself. If you have a family which is dependant on your income and if have various commitments to fulfill throughout the year, then you might go through hell in your preparation period after quitting a high paying job. So I would say that if you really want to be a civil servant from your heart ,take time to get out of materialistic world before quitting the job.. Try to lead a simple life and make some savings. And if at all you start preparing, do not look back and feel that you have made a bad decision. Do not regret. Push acceleration and go in full speed in preparation and be very confident even though it might seem stupid. Believe me confidence is all you require for this preparation. And have patience.. If you are skeptical about the decision, I think you should co Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:07:27.158Z"),
    "question" : "Should I be preparing for UPSC by quitting a well paying job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035df300c817f0398fa06b8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-strategies-for-preparing-UPSC-besides-job?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:08:00.368Z"),
    "question" : "What are the strategies for preparing UPSC besides job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035df460c817f0398fa06e2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-difference-between-jobs-in-UPSC-and-PCS?-",
    "answer" : "As the name suggest UPSC conduct the examination for Central government/ central PSUs…and Posting will be given to any part of India. appointee is Hon’ble President of India so he can only dismiss you from your job. Service conditions, promotion policy, Paybands and allowance are given as per central government provisions….. state PSC conduct the examination for state government/ state PSUs…and Posting will be given to any part of respective state. appointee is Hon’ble Governor of state so he can only dismiss you from your job…. Service conditions, promotion policy, Paybands and allowance are given as per state government provisions…..",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:08:22.181Z"),
    "question" : "What is the difference between jobs in UPSC and PCS? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035df5a0c817f0398fa06ee"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-Bhavesh-Mishra-managed-his-UPSC-preparation-with-his-job?-",
    "answer" : "Anubhav Sangwan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:08:42.064Z"),
    "question" : "How Bhavesh Mishra managed his UPSC preparation with his job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035df6d0c817f0398fa06fa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Are-all-jobs-in-UPSC-services-classified-as-Group-A?-",
    "answer" : "Group A services 1 Indian Administrative Service 2 Indian Foreign Service 3 Indian Police Service 4 Indian P & T Accounts & Finance Service 5 Indian Audit and Accounts Service 6 Indian Revenue Service (Customs and Central Excise) 7 Indian Defence Accounts Service 8 Indian Revenue Service (I.T.) 9 Indian Ordnance Factories Service (Assistant Works Manager, Administration) 10 Indian Postal Service 11 Indian Civil Accounts Service 12Indian Railway Traffic Service 13 Indian Railway Accounts Service 14 Indian Railway Personnel Service 15 Indian Railway Protection Force (Assistant Security Commissioner) 16 Indian Defence Estates Service 17 Indian Information Service (Junior Grade) 18 Indian Trade Service, Group 'A' (Gr. III) 19 Indian Corporate Law Service Group B services 20 Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service  Continue Reading Group A services 1 Indian Administrative Service 2 Indian Foreign Service 3 Indian Police Service 4 Indian P & T Accounts & Finance Service 5 Indian Audit and Accounts Service 6 Indian Revenue Service (Customs and Central Excise) 7 Indian Defence Accounts Service 8 Indian Revenue Service (I.T.) 9 Indian Ordnance Factories Service (Assistant Works Manager, Administration) 10 Indian Postal Service 11 Indian Civil Accounts Service 12Indian Railway Traffic Service 13 Indian Railway Accounts Service 14 Indian Railway Personnel Service 15 Indian Railway Protection Force (Assistant Security Commissioner) 16 Indian Defence Estates Service 17 Indian Information Service (Junior Grade) 18 Indian Trade Service, Group 'A' (Gr. III) 19 Indian Corporate Law Service Group B services 20 Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:09:01.226Z"),
    "question" : "Are all jobs in UPSC services classified as Group A? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dfcc0c817f0398fa0765"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-toughest-job-in-the-UPSC-CSE?-",
    "answer" : "Sajeed Mahboob, B.Tech from Indian Institute of Technology Ropar (2015)Updated 2 years ago · Author has 85 answers and 1.9M answer viewsWhat was your toughest moment during entire UPSC CSE preparation and how you overcome that one? Sajeed Mahboob Disclaimer 1: This answer contains very important informations for CSE aspirants, especially for those who come from humble background or those who want to be independent in their expenses. So, this answer is gonna be little long, bear with me. Disclaimer 2: Those who don't like my answers or writings for any reason whatsoever, are advised to downvote or report the answers or my account to Quora. I'm getting lot of futile criticisms, abuses, flaks and even threats in messages, comments and even in anonymous answers. I'm here to help those who are in serious need of little guidance or advice of my expertise. If you can't help, don't stop others from doing that. Coming to question, what is my toughest moment during entire preparation of CSE? Well, I come from a humble background and hence in o Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:10:36.923Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the toughest job in the UPSC CSE? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dfdd0c817f0398fa0771"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-kind-of-a-resume-would-be-considered-good-for-a-UPSC-aspirant?-",
    "answer" : "When the candidate is of art background a good marks of above 80% works. But for candidate, from medical or from technical background, they expect a lot more from them.They want a technical or a medical candidate to have good knowledge of his her branch and they even ask questions profoundly from the subjects what he had studied during college.This much is not enough they also seek for above 8 CGPA. Abhijit Mondal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:10:53.676Z"),
    "question" : "What kind of a resume would be considered good for a UPSC aspirant? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035dff10c817f0398fa0781"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-physical-fitness-mandatory-for-UPSC-aspirants?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Is physical fitness mandatory for UPSC aspirants?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:11:13.116Z"),
    "question" : "Is physical fitness mandatory for UPSC aspirants? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e0020c817f0398fa07a5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-you-list-out-the-jobs-under-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Raj Rathore",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:11:30.840Z"),
    "question" : "Can you list out the jobs under UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e02a0c817f0398fa07c1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-posts-which-are-filled-by-the-UPSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Q: what are the job posts which are filled through upsc exam? Ans: The various posts offered through the UPSC Civil Services Exam are - Indian Administrative ServiceIndian Foreign ServiceIndian Revenue Service ( Customs & Central Excise, Gr.`A’ )Indian P & T Accounts & Finance Service, Gr.`AIndian Audit & Accounts Service, Gr.`A’Indian Defence Accounts Service, Gr. ‘A’Indian Revenue Service ( IT ), Gr. `A’Indian Ordnance Factories Service, Gr.`A’Indian Postal Service, Gr. ‘A’Indian Civil Accounts Service, Gr. ‘A’Indian Railway Accounts Service, Gr. ‘A’Indian Railway Personnel Service, Gr. ‘A’Indian Railway Traffic Service Group 'A'Indian Defence Estates Service Gr. 'A'Indian Information Service, Gr. 'A'Indian Trade Service Gr. 'A' ( Gr. III )Indian Corporate Law Service, Group 'A'Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service, Gr. 'B' ( Section Officers' Grade )Delhi, Andaman & Nicobar Islands, Lakshadweep, Daman & Diu and Dadra & Nagar Haveli Police Service, Gr.’B’Pondicherry Civil Service, ( Group B ) and many others.Hope this will help",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:12:10.077Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job posts which are filled by the UPSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e0550c817f0398fa07f5"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-a-29-year-old-start-preparation-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Suhail Noolkar i am the best person to answer this question. let me elaborate the common situation of early upsc aspirants mind screamersi have only one chance and my age was going to bar soonsome people crack the exam on first attempt, although it requires luck. Then why not you? I appeared for upsc 2013 when i had only one attempt (at that time upsc age limit was 30 years for general). Remember kismat ke naam ko to sab jaanate hai,lekin kismat me kyaa likhaa hai, bus allaah jaanataa hai - Akhtar ShiraniThe fact is no body knows what food he is going to have tonight, then how can you tell if you are going to crack ias or not that too after one year preparation?there are many talented people already tryingluck do not side the unprepared and timid. The trick is to be prepared and act whenever presenContinue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:12:53.404Z"),
    "question" : "Can a 29-year-old start preparation for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e07c0c817f0398fa0828"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-UPSC-being-in-a-private-job-having-different-shifts?-",
    "answer" : "Nikhil Srivas",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:13:32.553Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for UPSC being in a private job having different shifts? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e0900c817f0398fa0833"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-are-UPSC-jobs-dream-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Rajendra Kumar",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:13:52.166Z"),
    "question" : "Why are UPSC jobs dream jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e0c20c817f0398fa086e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-chemical-engineering-jobs-through-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:14:42.993Z"),
    "question" : "What are the chemical engineering jobs through UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1010c817f0398fa08ae"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-crack-the-UPSC-with-an-8-hour-job?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Kalyan Dev 4",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:15:45.051Z"),
    "question" : "Can I crack the UPSC with an 8-hour job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1130c817f0398fa08ba"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-leave-my-IT-job-to-prepare-for-UPSC-or-what-can-be-some-other-alternatives?-",
    "answer" : "Gp Pushpa Hi , Firstly, I would like for you to consider your choice to choose civil services ! I gave up my campus Recruitment exams after BE in information science in order to perceive civil services . I regretted it for 3 months while I simultaneously prepared for the exam and finally after 3 months I stopped blaming myself and owned my choice to become what I always wanted to be .So right now it might be very confusing for you to whether quit and prepare or prepare while you work . Well I suggest that you consider below options first and then decide . So that in later stages of your preparation you shouldn't regret your decision of quitting your job . Know that earning life and study life are two different roads . Question yourself why do you wish to be a civil servant ? Are you ready to change andContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:16:03.120Z"),
    "question" : "Should I leave my IT job to prepare for UPSC or what can be some other alternatives? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1260c817f0398fa08e2"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-job-experience-matter-in-a-UPSC-civil-services-interview?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Does job experience matter in a UPSC civil services interview?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:16:22.614Z"),
    "question" : "Does job experience matter in a UPSC civil services interview? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1380c817f0398fa08eb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-UPSC-along-with-a-12-hourjob?-",
    "answer" : "Sarvesh Dubey That seems difficult isn't it ? And it is actually difficult. So will you actually quit? Will you compromise with your dreams? Will you do things that aren't mad for you? Will you be really satisfied with your activities? Will you let someone inside you say yourself a loser? And lastly will you not complete your dreams? Is your motivation long lasting? Answer these questions and if you find answer then you'll surely be not wanting such an external motivation to do so. I am not any professional and also I am just a 12 grade pass student that will be a future nitian I really want to code in my future ahead and you know my branch of study will be chemical and that's not it, I have to change my branch so that I can be in CSE next year but I can't wait for 1 long year for coding professionally. I am not g Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:16:40.248Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for UPSC along with a 12 hourjob? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1490c817f0398fa0904"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-the-UPSC-IAS-a-safe-job?-",
    "answer" : "It provides you financial security. Working hours might be long depending upon posting, but NOT many IAS officers die or sustain injuries while working on duty. You are not supposed to fight Naxalism or kill terrorists. Its just administration.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:16:57.636Z"),
    "question" : "Is the UPSC IAS a safe job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e15e0c817f0398fa0931"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC-with-other-full-time-work?-",
    "answer" : "Hiren Dave See Dear, Some people spend many hours but does not get successful. But there are some people with continue their job and some people who also give full time and crack the exam. So from this reviews hours is not going to matter or calculate. First of all, Start initially reading day to day and get idea of certain things which subject are from your background it doesn’t take a lot of time but which subject are new and not from your filed will take a lot of time so that will vary person to person. Give daily one hour to current events. Then which time is left you can divide in two parts, one type you can do like read only one subject at one time like if you are reading polity so read polity only, if you are doing mathematics do mathematics only. Second type will be like you can read different s Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:17:18.002Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare for the UPSC with other full-time work? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1740c817f0398fa093b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-joining-a-job-affect-my-UPSC-Civil-Services-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Mudit Gupta, Unacademy Educator |Engineer | LAMP Fellow| CLC (Law Fac,Du)Answered 3 years ago · Author has 372 answers and 1.3M answer viewsWill joining a job affect my UPSC Civil Services preparation? Mudit Gupta",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:17:40.572Z"),
    "question" : "Will joining a job affect my UPSC Civil Services preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1870c817f0398fa0949"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-jobs-available-after-failing-the-UPSC-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  What are the jobs available after failing the UPSC exam?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:17:59.755Z"),
    "question" : "What are the jobs available after failing the UPSC exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1ad0c817f0398fa097a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-crack-the-UPSC-with-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "Shubham Satyam, Published author | CSE Mains'19, '20*Answered 2 years ago · Author has 615 answers and 2.3M answer viewsIs it possible to do a job simultaneously with UPSC preparation because I want to do a job for a few years along with my UPSC preparation? Shubham Satyam Tried for 2 years. COULDN'T PREPARE. Left the job to start afresh. UPSC preparation had been in the back of my mind since college. But, I wasn't serious in the sense that I never studied with a plan. Some days, I'd randomly read articles on IR on the internet for hours. Other days, I'd waste time doing things that were deemed ‘important’ during the college period. Some days, I'd read The Hindu and then, stop following it altogether for 15–20 days or so. You see. It was for fun then. I joined an IT company after college. Few months down, I asked what am I doing? I spent the next few days researching about the exam. Read the Pre syllabus. Read and memorized GS1, GS2, GS3 and GS4 syllabus. I had no doubt regarding the optional- had to be PSIR! (Courtesy- Months spent on IDSA, Foreignaffairs.com,  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:18:37.321Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to crack the UPSC with a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 33 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1be0c817f0398fa0986"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-a-Hindi-medium-student-crack-the-UPSC-without-coaching?-",
    "answer" : "A to A. In a first forget the Hindi medium thing from your mind. UPSC don't discriminate any one by their respective medium. All are equal before UPSC. So just forget this thing and start preparing. I'm preparing for UPSC (IAS) from sometime. I have studied in one of the famous English medium coaching for sometime and secondly taken regular classes in renowned HINDI medium coaching. After completion of my classes and spending so much time and Nice money in Delhi. I have learned some of the things. Here I want to share… The most important thing in UPSC is not what to study…the most important is what NOT to study.You are your own coaching institute. Self study.Memorise UPSC syllabus by heart..by Mind…from anywhere. You may feel it not that important…but its most important thing. Just memorise it Continue Reading A to A. In a first forget the Hindi medium thing from your mind. UPSC don't discriminate any one by their respective medium. All are equal before UPSC. So just forget this thing and start preparing. I'm preparing for UPSC (IAS) from sometime. I have studied in one of the famous English medium coaching for sometime and secondly taken regular classes in renowned HINDI medium coaching. After completion of my classes and spending so much time and Nice money in Delhi. I have learned some of the things. Here I want to share… The most important thing in UPSC is not what to study…the most important is what NOT to study.You are your own coaching institute. Self study.Memorise UPSC syllabus by heart..by Mind…from anywhere. You may feel it not that important…but its most important thing. Just memorise it Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:18:54.589Z"),
    "question" : "How can a Hindi medium student crack the UPSC without coaching? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 34 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e1ec0c817f0398fa09bf"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Did-Roman-Saini-leave-his-job-to-prepare-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Roman Saini",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:19:40.629Z"),
    "question" : "Did Roman Saini leave his job to prepare for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 35 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2190c817f0398fa09fa"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-UPSC-the-ultimate-job?-",
    "answer" : "UPSC is not a job. It is an institution. 6",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:20:25.260Z"),
    "question" : "Is UPSC the ultimate job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 36 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e22c0c817f0398fa0a04"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Do-people-leave-their-jobs-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Many people do so because of the lure of the prestigious jobeg Gaurav Agrawal 2013 topper in CSE left his job in New York And many more examples",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:20:44.082Z"),
    "question" : "Do people leave their jobs for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 37 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2680c817f0398fa0a44"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Could-preparing-for-the-UPSC-be-useful-on-other-jobs-if-we-fail-in-the-exam?-",
    "answer" : "Lokesh Yadav Abdullah",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:21:44.489Z"),
    "question" : "Could preparing for the UPSC be useful on other jobs if we fail in the exam? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 38 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2830c817f0398fa0a5c"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-prepare-for-UPSC-with-a-9-9pm-job?-",
    "answer" : "Questions Rahishuddin Khan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:22:11.189Z"),
    "question" : "How can one prepare for UPSC with a 9-9pm job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 39 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2a30c817f0398fa0a8a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-job-prospects-for-failed-upsc-candidates?-",
    "answer" : "Options which come to mind1. Tutions 2. Try going into data analytics field, see the basic requirements - do a SAS certification, learn sql, excel analytics techniques etc - you can give 2 months time to it - courses are available online - check coursera, edx etcThen try to join a start up - try acing the interview in one go - once you get 1-2 years experience - switch to a bigger company. Hope this helps Viswanath Balakrishnan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:22:43.205Z"),
    "question" : "What are the job prospects for failed upsc candidates? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 40 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2c30c817f0398fa0aa0"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-benefits-and-allowances-of-UPSC-CAPF-job?-",
    "answer" : "Sagar, OFFICER at Central Armed Police ForcesAnswered 8 months ago · Author has 55 answers and 101.9K answer viewsWhat are the benefits and allowances of UPSC CAPF job? Sagar Being a CAPF gazetted officer you will be entitled for all the facilities more or less equal to other dept officers some are as 1.Accomodation type 4 for family ,improve after the promotion(CO type 5 and bunglow for above ) 2.Vehicle 3.Canteen faciltiy 4.Being an AC you will be deployed as company commander and he is tiger of his company and a single leaf can't move with out his order and he is commander of more than 100 men who always ready to do anything on your one order. Besides this ,you are entitled for pay and lots of allowances or monetary benefits subject to area of deployment .You can check the salary slip uploaded below showing some allowances and many more which are excluded .It is slip of an AC of 2017.  Hope it will help …. Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:23:15.591Z"),
    "question" : "What are the benefits and allowances of UPSC CAPF job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 41 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e2f90c817f0398fa0adc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Why-should-I-quit-my-job-to-prepare-for-the-UPSC-CSE?-",
    "answer" : "Sneha Sharma, studied The Arts at University of DelhiAnswered 3 years agoWhy should I quit my job to prepare for the UPSC CSE? Sneha Sharma",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:24:09.849Z"),
    "question" : "Why should I quit my job to prepare for the UPSC CSE? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 42 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e31c0c817f0398fa0b0e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Does-anyone-cleared-UPSC-while-doing-job-in-MNC?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:24:44.612Z"),
    "question" : "Does anyone cleared UPSC while doing job in MNC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 43 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3420c817f0398fa0b40"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-possible-to-clear-the-UPSC-in-one-year-with-a-full-time-job?-",
    "answer" : "Well, you have put more than 1 question in a single question, like UPSC does :), I would try to answer them one by one. Can somebody help me with finding good books online and any helpful tips?Yes, there are lot of people to help you but you have to do your part. What could be the best optional?You have decide this. IMO, optional is like spouse. Do not let some one decide, check pros, cons and then decide yourself, because you are going to spend a lot of time with your spouse :) (Optional) Is it possible to clear UPSC in one year, with a full time job? No, you have to blame UPSC for this, because the whole process(prelims to final results) itself takes a year to complete. If you are average student, you may have to give more than 1 attempt and 2 attempts will eat your 3 years of life. If you Continue Reading Well, you have put more than 1 question in a single question, like UPSC does :), I would try to answer them one by one. Can somebody help me with finding good books online and any helpful tips?Yes, there are lot of people to help you but you have to do your part. What could be the best optional?You have decide this. IMO, optional is like spouse. Do not let some one decide, check pros, cons and then decide yourself, because you are going to spend a lot of time with your spouse :) (Optional) Is it possible to clear UPSC in one year, with a full time job? No, you have to blame UPSC for this, because the whole process(prelims to final results) itself takes a year to complete. If you are average student, you may have to give more than 1 attempt and 2 attempts will eat your 3 years of life. If you Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:25:22.128Z"),
    "question" : "Is it possible to clear the UPSC in one year with a full-time job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 44 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3530c817f0398fa0b48"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-prepare-for-UPSC-after-getting-into-SBI-PO?-",
    "answer" : "Anuj Jindal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:25:39.880Z"),
    "question" : "How can one prepare for UPSC after getting into SBI PO? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 45 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3690c817f0398fa0b5a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-UPSC-is-job-or-aim-for-person?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Anshu Sharma Inderjeet Arya",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:26:01.606Z"),
    "question" : "Is UPSC is job or aim for person? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 46 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e38a0c817f0398fa0b89"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-handle-my-UPSC-preparation-while-working-in-a-10-hour-job-timing?-",
    "answer" : "Bharadwaj Raj I agree , it's a little bit tough to prepare for UPSC while working. But, don't get discouraged, just try this. 1. Choose your optionals which you love most. It reduces the preparation time and you study enthusiastically. 2. Join in a coaching centre, due to which you bound to attend the classes on daily basis and you study everyday automatically. 3. Priortize your needs, just go to bed early and raise early, which gives you a greenness. 4. As you are a software employee you will get weekend for two days, put your hardwork on these two days. 5. Avoid mobile, movies and reduce phone calls. But meet your close friends maximum once in a weak. 6. Call or meet your parents frequently which reduce stress. 7. And finally, don't mess up with your life on unnecessary crushes on girls. All the best.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:26:34.749Z"),
    "question" : "How do I handle my UPSC preparation while working in a 10 hour job timing? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 47 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3c70c817f0398fa0bcd"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-good-to-prepare-for-the-UPSC-along-with-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "Rohit Chauhan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:27:35.541Z"),
    "question" : "Is it good to prepare for the UPSC along with a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 48 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3d90c817f0398fa0bd9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-true-that-Dhruv-Rathee-topped-the-UPSC-Civil-Service-but-declined-the-job-to-be-a-YouTuber?-",
    "answer" : "Thanks for your request! I have been watching Dhruv Rathi's YouTube channel for the last one year.  From time to time, he has shared a lot about himself with his channel's audience. He says about himself in a video that he hails from Haryana and does his studies abroad. His channel has also been around four years now and he is not in India even before that. This means that even if he never sat in the Civil Services Examination, there was no question of tapping. If you have heard something like this, it can be just a rumor. Zain Moosvi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:27:53.547Z"),
    "question" : "Is it true that Dhruv Rathee topped the UPSC Civil Service but declined the job to be a YouTuber? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 49 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e3eb0c817f0398fa0bea"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-types-of-jobs-will-I-get-after-cracking-the-UPSC-Main?-",
    "answer" : "Kushal Dhayal",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:28:11.985Z"),
    "question" : "Which types of jobs will I get after cracking the UPSC Main? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 50 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e40f0c817f0398fa0c1a"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-prepare-for-UPSC-CSE-Prelims-in-a-month-with-a-9-5-job?-",
    "answer" : "Mainak Ghosh, Civil Servant at Government of India (2018-present)Answered 1 year agoHow can I prepare for UPSC CSE Prelims in a month with a 9-5 job? Mainak Ghosh",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:28:47.698Z"),
    "question" : "How can I prepare for UPSC CSE Prelims in a month with a 9-5 job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}
/* 1 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4200c817f0398fa0c27"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-job-will-a-person-get-if-he-fails-in-the-UPSC-interview-as-an-IAS-candidate?-",
    "answer" : "Prem Kumar",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:29:04.604Z"),
    "question" : "What job will a person get if he fails in the UPSC interview as an IAS candidate? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 2 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4350c817f0398fa0c51"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-job-profile-of-an-enforcement-officer-in-the-UPSC-EPFO?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  How do I prepare for a UPSC interview for a position as an EPFO enforcement officer?",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:29:25.098Z"),
    "question" : "What is the job profile of an enforcement officer in the UPSC EPFO? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 3 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e46c0c817f0398fa0c8e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC-during-SSC-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Arpit Sharma, Cleared SSC CGL 2016 as AAO in CAGAnswered 3 years ago · Author has 904 answers and 8M answer viewsWhich SSC CGL post is best suited for the UPSC? Arpit Sharma Assistant Section Officer in Central Secretariat Service(CSS). Best SSC CGL post when it comes to UPSC preparation. Read further to be on same page as me . Every year SSC comes with 400–500 vacancies for this post. The competition is a bit tough but still its easier to get this post compared to others like MEA, ITI, Examiner etc (Cutoff a bit lower due to CPT ). Now let’s discuss why this is the best post for a UPSC aspirant? The posting is always in New Delhi. Half the work is done when there is a good start !!New Delhi is undoubtedly the mecca of UPSC CSE preparation. One can get himself/herself enrolled in best coaching available.( From ALS to Vajiram, everybody is here).Availability to best study material (From standard books to printed material of coaching notes, everything at stone’s tContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:30:20.550Z"),
    "question" : "How do I prepare for the UPSC during SSC jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 4 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4800c817f0398fa0c98"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-a-good-idea-to-switch-jobs-while-preparing-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:30:40.106Z"),
    "question" : "Is it a good idea to switch jobs while preparing for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 5 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4a40c817f0398fa0cb1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-I-clear-the-UPSC-exam-with-a-job?-",
    "answer" : "Preparation of UPSC with job is quiet difficult but you can do it by strict time table divided wisely between job and exam preparation and you should be deterministic and work hard for exam.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:31:16.342Z"),
    "question" : "How can I clear the UPSC exam with a job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 6 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4bc0c817f0398fa0cda"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-job-should-I-get-with-the-1000th-rank-in-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "One of the Group B services, most likely. They are the following:- Group B Services Armed Forces Headquarters Civil Service (AFHCS)Pondicherry Civil ServicePondicherry Police ServiceThe DANICS and DANIPS are Group B services as well, but their cut off is often higher than some of the Group A services. Civil Services Examination (India) - Wikipedia",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:31:40.549Z"),
    "question" : "What job should I get with the 1000th rank in UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 7 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4d00c817f0398fa0cee"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-good-to-leave-TCS-job-and-prepare-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Use the sabbatical option. TCS will provide sabbatical leave for 2 years for higher studies. Talk with your HR. 3",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:32:00.643Z"),
    "question" : "Is it good to leave TCS job and prepare for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 8 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4e20c817f0398fa0d17"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Has-anybody-ever-cleared-UPSC-with-full-time-working-job-and-self-study?-",
    "answer" : "Namdev Pasme Bandana Pokhriyal, Rank – 83, Cleared UPSC Civil Services Without Quitting Job While Working as Excise Inspector for Past 4.5 Years So .. Here I go. .. this is my story.. I am working as a Central Excise Inspector for the past four and a half years. And the past two and a half years have been a juggle between work and study. In the beginning, things seemed too difficult. I vividly remember breaking down many times. But once I could figure out a plan and a time table on a daily basis, the tempo soon developed. I starting preparing a day by day time table and ensured that I acted in accordance with it. As my office timings almost consumed 8 hours of the day I tried to set practical targets as setting impossible target leads to nothing but frustration in case you are not able to finish it off. F Continue Reading Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:32:18.004Z"),
    "question" : "Has anybody ever cleared UPSC with full time working job and self study? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 9 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e4f20c817f0398fa0d1f"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-an-RBI-Grade-B-job-a-good-backup-for-the-UPSC-CSE?-",
    "answer" : "If your goal is only civil services then it is not advisable to join any organisation till you are eligible and can afford UPSC preparation. A large number of candidates come to join RBI as Grade B Officers after pursuing the preparation for Civil Services. First you will prepare for a year or so for Grade B and then again it will take some time. And most candidates tend to get relaxed after joining a government service. Leaves are limited either on probation or after probation period. There are 45 leaves in total in a year which cannot be availed in one go. If you think that after joining you will start preparation for civil services then it is difficult if not impossible. Many RBI Grade B officers and Assistants made it into civil services but the preparation they have done before joining the RBI plays very essential role. It is, therefore, not easy to start such preparation from scratch after joining the job. But it always depends on focus and dedication with utilization of available time and resources to get success.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:32:34.884Z"),
    "question" : "Is an RBI Grade B job a good backup for the UPSC CSE? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 10 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e51b0c817f0398fa0d3b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-best-government-jobs-in-India-expect-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Some of the best Government jobs in India apart from UPSC are- 1.Defence Services-Defence service job is another great option for people who want to do something for the country. It has one of the best promotion aspects.The aspirant is required to appear for NDA ,AFCAT to join thses services.The pay and perks vary from service to service.There is good accomodation,uniform allowance,free ration,maintainance allowance,transport allowance and pension after retirement.This job provides an aspirant with the opportunity to enter into the Indian Navy, Army and Air Force. 2.Public Sector Undertaking-The public sector undertakings employ on a large scale every year through different competitive exams.Some of the reputed PSU are ONGC, Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited (BHEL), NTPC limited, GAIL and MTN Continue Reading Some of the best Government jobs in India apart from UPSC are- 1.Defence Services-Defence service job is another great option for people who want to do something for the country. It has one of the best promotion aspects.The aspirant is required to appear for NDA ,AFCAT to join thses services.The pay and perks vary from service to service.There is good accomodation,uniform allowance,free ration,maintainance allowance,transport allowance and pension after retirement.This job provides an aspirant with the opportunity to enter into the Indian Navy, Army and Air Force. 2.Public Sector Undertaking-The public sector undertakings employ on a large scale every year through different competitive exams.Some of the reputed PSU are ONGC, Bharat Heavy Electricals Limited (BHEL), NTPC limited, GAIL and MTN Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:33:15.942Z"),
    "question" : "What are the best government jobs in India expect UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 11 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e5420c817f0398fa0d6b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-should-we-have-to-prepare-for-UPSC-along-with-job-of-7-hours?-",
    "answer" : "Anubhav Sangwan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:33:54.386Z"),
    "question" : "How should we have to prepare for UPSC along with job of 7 hours? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 12 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e56d0c817f0398fa0da1"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-the-best-peaceful-job-in-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Aryan Tiwari",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:34:37.807Z"),
    "question" : "What is the best peaceful job in the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 13 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e5970c817f0398fa0ddb"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-wise-to-prepare-for-the-SSC-CGL-and-get-a-job-then-go-for-the-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Odde Siva Kesavam Vishal Gupta",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:35:19.991Z"),
    "question" : "Is it wise to prepare for the SSC CGL and get a job then go for the UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 14 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e5a80c817f0398fa0de3"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Will-I-be-able-to-clear-UPSC-after-I-get-a-job-in-SSC?-",
    "answer" : "You should go ahead an prepare for SSC , if selected give Assistant in CSS as your first preference . This is a desk job and thus will give you plenty of time to prepare for UPSC exam . Moreover it is a 4600 grade pay job so your pay won't be that bad.  Conversely if you want to join IFS , you can select Assistant in MEA , through this after working for 10 years you will be promoted to Indian Foreign Service .  Best of luck . Danish Ranjan",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:35:36.689Z"),
    "question" : "Will I be able to clear UPSC after I get a job in SSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 15 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e5cd0c817f0398fa0dfe"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-better-to-take-the-UPSC-exam-after-some-sort-of-job-experience?-",
    "answer" : "I also had couple of friends who were in similar situation as yours. Let me attempt to help you find a solution for this. How strong is your desire to become a Civil servant? If you are sure that that's what you want to do then there is no point in going for a job. It will not be easy to prepare for UPSC while working. It takes lot of effort and hard work to clear UPSC and you need to work towards that. There is no need to play it safe, go full throttle in preparation and it will pay.",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:36:13.094Z"),
    "question" : "Is it better to take the UPSC exam after some sort of job experience? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 16 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e5de0c817f0398fa0e23"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-crack-UPSC-in-6-months-while-in-job?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Jeeth Paul Pawan Kumar Pandey",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:36:30.572Z"),
    "question" : "Can I crack UPSC in 6 months while in job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 17 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6260c817f0398fa0e6e"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC-by-working-in-a-bank?-",
    "answer" : "Yes! absolutely, you can do your preparation for the UPSC exam but you need proper guidance and the right strategy to clear the UPSC exam. Now, I tell you some rough approaches to start your preparation. As you said, You are a banking professional so I am assuming that you have gained knowledge of NCERTs and little currents affairs knowledge which will help in the UPSC exam as well. So let’s talk about how to approach- First of all, you will download the UPSC syllabus and Previous year question paper and read the syllabus only. Now maybe you have already downloaded the syllabus and thinking that I am not understand anything that is written in the syllabus and previous year papers, that’s fine for the first step. Now jump on the second step.Download/Buy all NCERTs from class 6 to 12.Now you havContinue Reading Yes! absolutely, you can do your preparation for the UPSC exam but you need proper guidance and the right strategy to clear the UPSC exam. Now, I tell you some rough approaches to start your preparation. As you said, You are a banking professional so I am assuming that you have gained knowledge of NCERTs and little currents affairs knowledge which will help in the UPSC exam as well. So let’s talk about how to approach- First of all, you will download the UPSC syllabus and Previous year question paper and read the syllabus only. Now maybe you have already downloaded the syllabus and thinking that I am not understand anything that is written in the syllabus and previous year papers, that’s fine for the first step. Now jump on the second step.Download/Buy all NCERTs from class 6 to 12.Now you havContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:37:42.451Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare for the UPSC by working in a bank? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 18 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e65a0c817f0398fa0ea8"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Should-I-quit-my-job-and-pursue-UPSC?Please-read-my-description-and-will-appreciate-suggestions-from-anyone-who-have-cleared-UPSC.-",
    "answer" : "Lavi Singh Though you appreciate an answer from a UPSC clearant yet I thought I could answer you…even I'm an aspirant like you. Regarding your job and the UPSC clearance, if you want to pursue your job then there is nothing wrong pursuing your preparations simultaneously. Instead of these cotton balls in air, I would quote a real life example of MR. Surendra Singh (CSE-2005) RANK-28, presently serving in BAREILLY (U.P). He was serving in ONGC when he had cleared this examination. Many people suggested him to drop out hos job but he didn't and continued preparing. He used to spend his nights preparing and sleep during the first break of morning. With sheer determination and toil he sailed off through the hardships. Even you can try it out Alagiri Bagavthi",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:38:34.498Z"),
    "question" : "Should I quit my job and pursue UPSC?Please read my description and will appreciate suggestions from anyone who have cleared UPSC. ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 19 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6730c817f0398fa0eb9"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Have-you-left-your-job-of-SBI-for-the-preparation-of-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:38:59.283Z"),
    "question" : "Have you left your job of SBI for the preparation of UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 20 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6840c817f0398fa0ec7"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Did-anyone-clear-the-UPSC-after-getting-a-job-as-through-the-SSC-CGL?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Saurabh Uttam 2",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:39:16.529Z"),
    "question" : "Did anyone clear the UPSC after getting a job as through the SSC CGL? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 21 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6b60c817f0398fa0f01"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-I-prepare-for-the-UPSC-CSE-while-I-am-joining-as-a-Bank-PO?-",
    "answer" : "Why not? People gonna tell you yes some of them going to say no. They will motivate you some of 'em will demotivate you. Question is does it even matter? It's a inner job mate. If you believe you can do it, yes you can do it. Period! I'm also working in the bank and i believe i can clear upsc, i know it's a long run and it will take so much effort but i never think that this can't be done. Good luck mate :) Km Rahul (राहुल कुशवाहा) (राहुल कुशवाहा)",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:40:06.826Z"),
    "question" : "Can I prepare for the UPSC CSE while I am joining as a Bank PO? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 22 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6cf0c817f0398fa0f2b"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-did-you-manage-your-UPSC-studies-while-working-in-a-company?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers  Aritra Bhattacharya (অরিত্র ভট্টাচার্য)",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:40:31.701Z"),
    "question" : "How did you manage your UPSC studies while working in a company? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 23 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e6f40c817f0398fa0f45"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-prepare-for-the-UPSC-CSE-with-a-9-5-job?-",
    "answer" : "Sumesh Chahal Dear Candidate, It is difficult but not impossible to prepare for the UPSC CSE while working. You have to be really smart with time management and utilization of resources, especially the internet. A job can be a constraint only if you don't know how to manage your time efficiently, but then you can't really prepare for CSE even if you leave your job because it's all about efficient management. On the other hand, working and preparing at the same time can be a great fulfilling experience in life. You are not dependent on anyone, and you get the feeling that you will shape your own destiny. In fact, there are some moments when you feel all-powerful and you think that you can achieve whatever you want. Invariably there will be some moments when you feel crushed between two rocks and feel like Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:41:08.918Z"),
    "question" : "How can one prepare for the UPSC CSE with a 9-5 job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 24 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e7070c817f0398fa0f6d"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/How-do-I-start-preparation-for-UPSC-without-coaching-and-with-8-hours-job?-",
    "answer" : "Aishwarya I am going to suggest few things they might not relate to every professional but according to my understanding The best way to prepare for civil services exam is to prepare a plan, as per your respective profession. Like the real-life long distance love stories, dealing with the civil services, while working, is difficult. Work when you are working, eat when you are eating, sleep when you are sleeping, and most importantly, Study when you are studying. Only an effective plan can help you in maintaining a balance in your work and studies. Secondly, do not waste your time in searching different study material in the market. Instead, spend your time in preparing for the exam, by using the help of a reliable source. Set a schedule as per your liking and stick to it.Do selective reading but be thoruContinue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:41:27.667Z"),
    "question" : "How do I start preparation for UPSC without coaching and with 8 hours job? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 25 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e72e0c817f0398fa0f88"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-problems-can-women-face-in-UPSC-civil-services-jobs?-",
    "answer" : "Civilservice is a very demanding Job and problems can arise in any manner. When we are bureaucrats we may be straightforward or sometimes against some wealthy shots and we may be jagguled like balls in the hands of wealth and power but one who knows to survive and as well as perform their duties become the fit list officers. Problems faced by fit listers. Main problem is that you will have to have face frequent transfers. We will have work day and night sometimes days together if necessary. We will have to face some threatening and frequent warnings from authority above us if we are so straightforward Sometimes we may be very much bound to serve the needy that will find it hard to tackle with your family needs . The more common and important thing is that you will have to balance your personal and official problems. Sometimes you have to sacrifice your personal happiness More importantantly be ready to do whatever jobs assigned how ever risky or demanding it is . Sometimes you will be given a job for which you are over qualified or the jobs which will not feed your thirst to serve the people accept them and try to do your best. Try to serve the poor , BE BOLD TO QUESTION THE RICH EVEN. 9",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:42:06.709Z"),
    "question" : "What problems can women face in UPSC civil services jobs? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 26 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e7550c817f0398fa0fbc"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-there-any-non-transferable-job-after-clearing-upsc?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Sethuraman Ramanujam Riddhi Mishra",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:42:45.106Z"),
    "question" : "Is there any non transferable job after clearing upsc? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 27 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e77a0c817f0398fa0fef"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/What-is-it-like-to-quit-a-job-in-IT-industry-and-start-preparing-for-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Satabdi Das",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:43:22.215Z"),
    "question" : "What is it like to quit a job in IT industry and start preparing for UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 28 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e79b0c817f0398fa1002"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Which-is-the-best-government-job-for-UPSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Ajay Sah Ritesh Saini",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:43:55.151Z"),
    "question" : "Which is the best government job for UPSC preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 29 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e7d70c817f0398fa1042"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-we-assume-that-all-those-who-attend-UPSC-final-interview-will-definitely-get-any-job-under-UPSC?-",
    "answer" : "Include Related Answers Vedansh Mishra 1",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:44:55.224Z"),
    "question" : "Can we assume that all those who attend UPSC final interview will definitely get any job under UPSC? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 30 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e7e90c817f0398fa1052"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Can-one-take-an-RBI-grade-B-job-as-a-backup-for-UPSC-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:45:13.083Z"),
    "question" : "",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 31 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e7fc0c817f0398fa1077"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-a-bank-clerk-job-decent-for-the-UPSC-civil-service-exam-preparation?-",
    "answer" : "Chander Kanta Gariyali",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:45:32.296Z"),
    "question" : "Is a bank clerk job decent for the UPSC civil service exam preparation? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}

/* 32 */
{
    "_id" : ObjectId("6035e8130c817f0398fa1086"),
    "job_link" : "https://www.quora.com/Is-it-good-to-have-a-job-or-secured-life-before-preparing-for-UPSC-exams?-",
    "answer" : "Kumaraswamy S Vasan, Worked at Indian Administrative ServiceAnswered 3 years ago · Author has 1.6K answers and 8.3M answer viewsIs it good to have a job or secured life before preparing for UPSC exams? Kumaraswamy S Vasan It depends on your economic background and the current level of your motivation to take the plunge. If you are in acute need of a job to support your parents or other family members, and if there is definite possibility of getting a reasonably good job in the immediate future, you may start your preparation later on. Otherwise, it is not a good idea to defer your preparation. You can also simultaneously try to get a suitable job. If you are sufficiently motivated at the moment for the UPSC exam, it is unwise to delay the process. Strike the iron while it is hot, as the saying goes. There is no one-size-fit-all solution to prepare for and succeed in CSE. It varies from person to person. You should assess your priorities and decide your course of action with due consideration to the prevailing  Continue Reading",
    "date" : ISODate("2021-02-24T05:45:55.014Z"),
    "question" : "Is it good to have a job or secured life before preparing for UPSC exams? ",
    "source" : "Quora"
}